Finding Aid for the Tulancingo (Hildago, Mexico) Manuscript Collection, 1567-1882 LSC.2073
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Post-1852 manuscripts, 1854-1877; 5 boxes
  - El C. Jose Panfilo Gomez contra el C. Mariano Vera Gomez, 1872-1880; 70 leaves (Box 8, Folder 8)
    Dispute over payment of an outstanding mortgage owed by Mariano Vera Gomez to Jose Panfilo Gomez.
  - Intestado de Doña María Nicolasa Hernandez, 1874; 9 leaves (Box 8, Folder 9)
    Probate documents consisting of petitions and a declaration of an existing death record for intestate María Nicolasa Hernandez who died of a pulmonary condition. Declaration of death indicates that decedent was the daughter of Antonio Hernandez.
  - [Civil action pertaining to a land title and property boundaries involving parties María Gertrudis Castro and Mariano Villegas], 1874-1875; 4 leaves (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - [Civil suit over money initiated by Jose Diomicio Soto versus Don Galan relating to petitioner's claim for rights to the assets of decedent Cornelio Mendoza and to contest the intestacy of decedent Mendoza], 1875; 2 leaves (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - [Request for testimony concerning a document that memorializes the sale of land by Candelaria Linarte to Antonia Menezes, as requested by Manuel Fernandez], 1880; 2 leaves (Box 8, Folder 12)
    Manuel Fernandez was the husband of Antonia Menezes and he submitted the petition for testimony because of a dispute over the plot involving Cristobal Cabrera and Jose Maria Chavez.
  - [Petition memorializing satisfaction of debts owed to Dr. Don Antonio Martinez by Maria Ygnacia Escorcia de Martinez and her children, as legal heirs of Mariano Martinez], 1881; 2 leaves (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - [Petition submitted by Regina Cossio V. de Martinez, executor of the estate and widow of Ponciano Martinez, in a civil suit initiated by Delfino Vera], 1881; 2 leaves (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Testimonio del testamento de Doña Joséfa Estrada, 1873-1875; 129 leaves (Box 8, Folder 15)
    Testimony concerning the will and testament of Doña María Joséfa Estrada, an Indian. Folder also contains related documents for the estate of María Joséfa Ortega, Estrada's granddaughter who died before Estrada. File contains interrogatories, petitions, etc.
  - Intestado de D[oñ]a Joséfa Ortega, 1873-1876; 163 leaves (Box 8, Folder 16)
    Probate documents for María Joséfa Ortega, granddaughter to María Joséfa Estrada (see Folder 14 above), including various receipts, balance sheets for legal fees and expenses, estate accounting, and petitions. Documents speak about Gabriel Ormaechea.
  - [Probate documents relating to the estate of María Joséfa Ortega], 1875-1878; 54 leaves (Box 8, Folder 17)
    Probate documents relating to the estate of María Joséfa Ortega.
  - El C. Lic. José M[arí]a Carvajal como apoderado de D[oñ]a Joséfa Estrada sobre que se declare ... el testamento de D[oñ]a Joséfa Ortega, 1873-1874; 79 leaves (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - El C. Manuel Ortega dejando derecho a los bienes al intestado a D[oñ]a Joséfa Ortega, 1874-1877; 74 leaves (Box 8, Folder 19)
    Probate documents including interrogatories, petitions, and an inventory of assets and debts relating to the estate of María Joséfa Ortega. Folder also contains documents from the case captioned: "Sobre administracion de los bienes de la finada Doña Joséfa Ortega"